(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-14T01:22:04.402644",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆様、本日は轟はじめ生誕祭2025にお越しくださいまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you so much for coming to Todoroki Hajime Birthday Live 2025 today.
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Before the show begins, we have a few requests and notices for everyone.
当配信は一部収録を含みますが、生配信部分もございますので、いっぱいコメントして盛り上げてください！
This stream includes some pre-recorded parts, but there are also live portions, so please leave lots of comments to hype it up!
番長も見えてるんですけど...
Bancho can see you too, though...
うーん、じゃあ...番長！きゃー！きちゃー！おー！きちゃー！
Hmm, well... Bancho! Kyaa! It's here! Oooh! It's here!
うわー、こんちくわー！ありがたさまーす！
Woah, hello everyone! Thank you very much!
テレビやパソコン、スマートフォン等の前での飲食は可能ですが、キーボードにこぼさないようにお気をつけください。
Eating and drinking in front of your TV, computer, or smartphone is permitted, but please be careful not to spill on your keyboard.
当配信のハッシュタグは #轟はじめ生誕祭2025 です！SNSでたくさんポストしてください！
The hashtag for this stream is #TodorokiHajimeBirthdayLive2025! Please post a lot on SNS!
開演中、パソコンやスマートフォン等による写真撮影、大歓迎です！たくさんポストして盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです！
Taking photos with your PC or smartphone during the show is warmly welcomed! We'd be so happy if you post a lot and hype it up!
それでは開演までしばらくお待ちください！
Now then, please wait a moment until the show begins!
うりゃ！皆様、本日は轟はじめ生誕祭2025にお越しくださいまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Uryah! Ladies and gentlemen, thank you so much for coming to Todoroki Hajime Birthday Live 2025 today.
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Before the show begins, we have a few requests and notices for everyone.
当配信は一部収録を含みますが、生配信部分もございますので、いっぱいコメントしてくれると、すごく嬉しいです！
This stream includes some pre-recorded parts, but there are also live portions, so I'd be super happy if you leave lots of comments!
じゃあ、じゃあ、2周目たしかー...ワクワク！2回目！いいだろ、2回言っても！ありがとね！
Well, well, the second round is surely... exciting! Second time! It's fine to say it twice! Thank you!
テレビやパソコン、スマートフォンの前での飲食は可能ですが、キーボードにこぼさないようにお気をつけください。
Eating and drinking in front of your TV, computer, or smartphone is permitted, but please be careful not to spill on your keyboard.
当配信のハッシュタグは #轟はじめ生誕祭2025 です！
The hashtag for this stream is #TodorokiHajimeBirthdayLive2025!
SNSでたくさんポストしてください！
Please post a lot on SNS!
開演中、パソコンやスマートフォン等による写真撮影も、あの、大歓迎なので、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱいポストしてください！
Taking photos with your PC or smartphone during the show is also, um, warmly welcomed, so please post lots, lots, lots, and lots!
それでは開演まで、しばらく、もうちょっと、お待ちください！
Now then, please wait just a little bit longer until the show starts!
ヘトヘトならば
If you're totally exhausted,
謝ってもムダ
apologizing is useless.
何がしたいかわからん
I don't know what I want to do,
もううんざりだ
I'm already fed up.
バカバカだまったく
Totally ridiculous, really.
あぁ 息苦しい世界だわ
Ah, what a suffocating world this is.
Hey! 1, 2, 3からカウンター
Hey! Countering from 1, 2, 3,
シャイなバーテン ゾンビに頼んだ
asked the shy bartender zombie.
まやかし あやかしのジュレビア
Deceptive, mysterious julep beer,
天然モノのディスピタンサ
a natural-born dispitansa.
暴れる準備は決まって
Ready to go wild,
派手なイントロダクション 唸った
the flashy introduction roared.
有名なパーティーが始まった
The famous party has begun.
あっかんべーのべー
Sticking out my tongue,
またべーべーべー
again, bleh bleh bleh!
うるさい
Shut up,
めんどくさいな
how bothersome!
もうイヤイヤイヤイヤ
Oh, I hate it, I hate it!
Oh あっかんべーのべー
Oh, sticking out my tongue,
またべーべーべー
again, bleh bleh bleh!
権利主張
Claiming rights,
関わんないよ
I won't get involved,
だるいだけ
it's just a hassle.
Oh 揺れる 揺れる 宣言
Oh, a swaying, swaying declaration,
圧倒的だな 宣言
an overwhelmingly bold declaration!
まだまだ踊ってよ
Keep on dancing,
ご唱和
chant along!
Oh 揺れる 揺れる 宣言
Oh, a swaying, swaying declaration,
圧倒的だな 宣言
an overwhelmingly bold declaration!
タラタタ ララタタ
Tara tata rara tata
ララララ
Ra ra ra ra
清廉潔白 私の過去には何の過ちもございません
Pure and blameless, there are no mistakes in my past.
分厚くなってきたルールブック
The rulebook is getting thicker,
見逃したときにはバンジーキュース
missed a beat and it's a bungee jump tight spot!
ビックリ精度のサーチライト
A searchlight of shocking precision,
それ外枠が一番怖いよ
"that's dangerous" is what scares me most!
レッドもイエローも関係ないのよ
Red or yellow cards don't matter,
一発退場
it's an immediate ejection!
はい お疲れ様
Alright, good job out there!
1 2 3からカウンター
Countering from 1, 2, 3,
熱いロックンロールを喰らった
hit with some red-hot rock 'n' roll!
インターリュードにのぼせるウィナー
A winner flush with excitement in the interlude,
バンギャのゾンビもパラパラ
even the band-gal zombies are dancing parapara!
偶像タイムも終わって
The idol time is over,
あっという間にこっから終盤だぞ
in the blink of an eye, we're in the home stretch!
ゾンビも猫も三途の川島も踊るだけ
Zombies, cats, even Kawashima from Sanzu River, just dance!
あっかんべーのべー
Sticking out my tongue,
またべーべーべー
again, bleh bleh bleh!
うるさい
Shut up,
めんどくさいな
how bothersome!
もうイヤイヤイヤイヤ
Oh, I hate it, I hate it!
Oh あっかんべーのべー
Oh, sticking out my tongue,
またべーべーべー
again, bleh bleh bleh!
権利主張
Claiming rights,
関わんないよ
I won't get involved,
だるいだけ
it's just a hassle.
Oh 揺れる 揺れる 宣言
Oh, a swaying, swaying declaration,
圧倒的だな 宣言
an overwhelmingly bold declaration!
まだまだ踊ってよ
Keep on dancing,
ご唱和
chant along!
Oh 揺れる 揺れる 宣言
Oh, a swaying, swaying declaration,
圧倒的だな 宣言
an overwhelmingly bold declaration!
タラタタ ララタタ
Tara tata rara tata
ララララ Yeah!
Ra ra ra ra Yeah!
Oh あっかんべーのべー
Oh, sticking out my tongue,
またべーべーべー
again, bleh bleh bleh!
うるさい
Shut up,
めんどくさいな
how bothersome!
もうイヤイヤイヤイヤ
Oh, I hate it, I hate it!
Oh あっかんべーのべー
Oh, sticking out my tongue,
またべーべーべー
again, bleh bleh bleh!
権利主張
Claiming rights,
関わんないよ
I won't get involved,
だるいだけ
it's just a hassle.
Oh 揺れる 揺れる 宣言
Oh, a swaying, swaying declaration,
圧倒的だな 宣言
an overwhelmingly bold declaration!
まだまだ踊ってよ
Keep on dancing,
ご唱和
chant along!
Oh 揺れる 揺れる 宣言
Oh, a swaying, swaying declaration,
圧倒的だな 宣言
an overwhelmingly bold declaration!
タラタタ ララタタ ララタタタ
Tara tata rara tata rara tatata
まだまだ笑えるが
I can still keep laughing,
弁弁弁しないで
so don't make excuses, excuse, excuses!
ラタタタラ
Ra ta ta ta ra
なんだか忙しく笑うタウン
A town that laughs somewhat hectically,
街抜ければバラバラ
breaking apart once leaving the streets.
暴れたゾンビと
Wild zombies,
転がるスター
and rolling stars,
飛んでいくしぐれ
drizzling rain flying past.
空から打ち抜くバニーガール
Bunny girl shooting down from the sky,
騒いでる様々
making a commotion in various ways.
あらあら危険なバランサー
My my, a dangerous balancer,
笑ったか緊張とスウーサイド
did you laugh, or is it tension and suicide?
この惨状 叩いて
Striking at this disastrous scene,
まだまだ行けるか
can we still keep going?
ハッピーエンドのチャイムが
If the chime of a happy ending
想像通りじゃないなら
isn't what you imagined,
塗り替えてしまうのさ
then we'll just rewrite it.
シュラシュラシュラシュラシュラ どうぞ
Shura shura shura shura shura, go right ahead.
敗北感とは
A sense of defeat
分かち合うもんではないから
isn't something to share with others,
蹴飛ばし 染め上げてごらん
so kick it away and paint over it.
そんなモンスター
Such a monster.
ラッタッタッタラ...
Rat-ta-ta-ta-ra...
正直こんなの味あるのかって
Honestly, I wondered if this had any meaning,
考えたところで堂々巡りで
but thinking about it just goes in circles.
あれもこれもそれも気になる気になる気になる
I'm curious about that, this, and everything!
それぞれ願う正義が絡み合う
Each person's desired justice entangles,
ああ まだまだいけそうだ
ah, looks like we can still go further.
ハッピーエンドのチャイムが
If the chime of a happy ending
想像通りじゃないなら
isn't what you imagined,
塗り替えてしまうのさ
then we'll just rewrite it.
シュラシュラシュラシュラシュラ どうぞ
Shura shura shura shura shura, go right ahead.
敗北感とは
A sense of defeat
分かち合うもんではないから
isn't something to share with others,
蹴飛ばし 染め上げてごらん
so kick it away and paint over it.
そんなモンスター
Such a monster.
ラッタッタッタラ...
Rat-ta-ta-ta-ra...
どこで何が起きるかわからない
You never know where or what will happen,
まだやり直せるかな
I wonder if we can still start over?
ハッピーエンドのチャイムが
If the chime of a happy ending
想像通りじゃないなら
isn't what you imagined,
塗り替えてしまうのさ
then we'll just rewrite it.
シュラシュラシュラシュラシュラ どうぞ
Shura shura shura shura shura, go right ahead.
敗北感とは
A sense of defeat
分かち合うもんではないから
isn't something to share with others,
蹴飛ばし 染め上げてごらん
so kick it away and paint over it.
そんなモンスター
Such a monster.
ラッタッタッタラ...
Rat-ta-ta-ta-ra...
はい！みんな、こんちこは～！
Hi! Everyone, konchikoha~!
初めての生誕祭来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to my first birthday live!
配信のハッシュタグは #一条莉々華生誕祭2025 です！
The stream hashtag is #RirikaBirthday2025!
たくさんポストしてくれたら嬉しいな～ トレンド入ってるわ！イェーイ！
I'd be so happy if you post a lot~ It's already trending! Yay!
ありがとうございます！嬉しい！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
そして、いろいろ初めて踊ったりするので、ぜひポストしてくれると嬉しいデス！
And since I'm dancing to a lot of things for the first time, please post about it!
えー、先ほどは『神っぽいな』と『OFFSIDE』という曲を聴いていただきました！
Um, earlier you listened to "Kamippoi na" and "OFFSIDE"!
どうでしたか？かっこよかったですか？
How was it? Was it cool?
ありがとう！こちらの曲もね、振付もめちゃくちゃ大好きなので、披露できて嬉しいデス！
Thank you! I love the songs and choreography so much, so I'm thrilled to perform them!
この後もまだたくさんあるので、一緒に楽しんでいってください！
There's still plenty more coming up, so please keep enjoying it with me!
次は、今かっこよかったけど、可愛くていたずらなパートデス！
Next up is a cute and mischievous part, following that cool performance!
それでは、いきましょう！
Well then, let's go!
Deal with the devil
[Title: Deal with the devil]
アップダウンは世の常
Ups and downs are the way of the world.
クズ引いたって動じない
Even if I draw a dud, I won't flinch.
肝心なのは Strong な Mind
What matters is a strong mind.
出し抜いて Survive
Outsmart them and survive.
行きつく先は Heaven or hell
Where we end up is heaven or hell.
この世界のルール たった一つ
There is only one rule in this world:
勝者こそが正義
the winner is justice.
女は度胸
A woman needs nerve.
焦らさせるのあいつを
Tease him, drive him wild.
やれること なんだってやる
I'll do whatever it takes.
あたしは賭け狂いのクイーン
I'm the gambling-crazed queen.
お見通しよ You doubt me
I see right through you, you doubt me.
読み切って レッツ Showdown
Read every move, let's showdown.
Deal with the devil
見透かして あたしのものにする
I'll see right through it and make it mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to every single strand of your hair.
A million dollars I'd say raise
震えてるわよ 坊や
You're trembling, little boy.
降ろさせはしないわ
I won't let you fold.
Deal with the devil
さあ Com'on 覚悟決めて
Now come on, make up your mind
震え高ぶる My heart
My heart is trembling and soaring
欲しがるようじゃね まだベイビー
Begging for it means you're still a baby
誰にも負けない
I won't lose to anyone
感じさせて Love me honey
Make me feel it, love me honey
あなた内緒だわ
It's a secret with you
ほら見せてあげる
Here, I'll show you
秘密って甘いの
Secrets are sweet, you know
仕掛けて罠に嵌めるわ
I'll set it up and trap you
油断誘うのよ 思考を止めたら ジ・エンド
Inviting carelessness; stop thinking and it's the end
何にも知らないような顔で
With a face that acts completely innocent
堕とすわあなたを
I'll bring you down
虚勢でしょうそれ You doubt me
That's just a bluff, isn't it? You doubt me
読み切って レッツ Showdown
Reading right through you, let's showdown
Deal with the devil
見逃さない どんな小さなズルだって
I won't miss a thing, no matter how small the trick
あたしの目はごまかされないわ
My eyes won't be fooled
A million dollars I'd say raise
勝った相手は骨まで
I'll love my defeated opponent...
愛し尽くしてあげる
...down to their very bones
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I won't let my targeted prey escape
唇濡らして頂くわ My babe
Wetting my lips, I'll take it, my babe
Oh yeah
Yeah
視線感じてるわ
I feel your eyes on me
お望みは んー 最後まで
What you want is... mm, until the very end
見てばかりいないで
Don't just stand there watching
嵐を起こしていかない？
Why don't we stir up a storm?
負けるのが怖い？ 弱いイジケ虫
Scared of losing? You weak coward
読み切って レッツ Showdown
Reading right through you, let's showdown
Deal with the devil
見すかして あたしのものにする
I'll see right through you and make you mine
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
Every single hair on your head, all of it
A million dollars I'd say raise
震えてるわよ 坊や
You're trembling, little boy
とことんまで行くわ
I'm going all the way
Deal with the devil
んー 興奮 たまらないわ スリル
Mmm, this excitement... I can't resist the thrill
誰にも触らせない この Money
I won't let anyone touch this money
A million dollars I'd say raise
さあ Com'on 覚悟決めて
Now come on, make up your mind
灰になるまで振って
Roll the dice until you turn to ash
欲しがるようじゃね まだベイビー
Begging for it means you're still a baby
誰にも負けない
I won't lose to anyone
感じさせて Love me honey
Make me feel it, love me honey
丸ノ内サディスティック
[Song: Marunouchi Sadistic]
報酬は入社後平行線で
Pay after joining stays on parallel lines
東京は愛せど何にも無い
Though I love Tokyo, it has nothing
リッケン620頂戴
Give me a Rickenbacker 620
19万も持って居ない
I don't even have 190,000 yen
御茶ノ水 マーシャルの匂いで飛んじゃって大変さ
In Ochanomizu, tripping on the smell of Marshall amps
毎晩絶頂に達して居るだけ
Just reaching ecstasy every single night
ラット1つを商売道具にしているさ
Using a single RAT pedal as my tool of the trade
そしたらベンジーが肺に映ってトリップ
Then Benzie is reflected in my lungs, tripping
最近は銀座で警官ごっこ
Lately playing cops in Ginza
国境は越えても盛者必衰
Even across borders, the prosperous must decline
領収書を書いて頂戴
Please write me a receipt
税理士なんて就いて居ない
I don't have a tax accountant
後楽園 将来僧になって結婚して欲しい
Korakuen, I want you to become a monk and marry me
毎晩寝具で遊戯するだけ
Just playing in bed every night
ピザ屋の彼女になってみたい
I want to try being a pizza shop girl
そしたらベンジー、あたしをグレッチで殴って
Then Benzie, hit me with your Gretsch
報酬は入社後平行線で
Pay remains flat even after joining,
東京は愛せど何にも無い
I love Tokyo, but there's nothing here.
領収書書いて頂戴
Please write me a receipt,
税理士等ついて居ない 後楽園
no tax accountant around in Kourakuen.
将来性になって結婚して欲しい
Become promising and marry me,
毎晩シングルで息をするだけ
just breathing alone every night.
ピザ屋の警官の常になってみたい
I want to be like a pizza delivery guy or cop.
そしたらベンジーがアタシをグレッチでぶって
Then Benjie would hit me with his Gretsch.
青噛んで行って頂戴
Chew a blue tablet and go,
終電で帰って代々木池袋
take the last train home via Yoyogi and Ikebukuro.
摩天楼の頂で飛んじゃって大変さ
Flying off the top of a skyscraper, it's wild.
毎晩絶頂に達しているだけ
Just reaching ecstasy every night.
納豆ひとつを商売道具にしているさ
Using a single pack of natto as a trade tool,
そしたらベンジーが肺に映ってたり
then Benjie gets reflected in my lungs.
将来性になって結婚して欲しい
Become promising and marry me,
毎晩シングルで息をするだけ
just breathing alone every night.
ピザ屋の警官の常になってみたい
I want to be like a pizza delivery guy or cop.
そしたらベンジーがアタシをグレッチでぶって
Then Benjie would hit me with his Gretsch.
はい！
Yeah!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
次はデストロパートです！
Next up is the Destroy Part!
今日も元気に行っていきまーす！
Let's go full energy today too!
今日も元気にドカンをきめたら ヨーラン背負ってリーゼント
Put on wide trousers today, wearing my jacket and quiff,
ツッパリ High School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
ソリも入れたし弁当も持ったし
Got my shaved side slits and brought my lunch,
かわいいあのコはクルクルパーマに 長めのスカート引きずって
That cute girl's got perm hair, dragging her long skirt.
ツッパリ High School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
おててつないで駅までしあわせ
Holding hands all the way to the station in bliss.
駅についたらアベックにガン飛ばし合い
At the station, trading glares with couples.
ツッパリ High School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
タイマン張りましょう赤テープ同士で
Let's duel one-on-one, red tape against red tape.
かあちゃん そんな心配すんなよ
Ma, don't worry about me so much.
勉強嫌いな俺だけどさ
I might hate studying, but...
人にはそれぞれ合った道ってもんがあんだよ
everyone's got a path that suits them.
もっと温かく大きな愛で
Look at me with warmer, bigger love,
愚かな僕を包んで欲しいな
and wrap up this foolish me.
なんだよ奏者 あそこにマブい女居るじゃんよ
What's up, Kanade? There's a fine chick over there!
どっちが男連れてんなぁ おい悪くないんじゃない？
Who's bringing a guy along? Hey, isn't she pretty bad?
電車に乗ったら便所に駆け込み 一駅だけのハッピータイム
Rush into the train bathroom for a happy time just for one stop.
ツッパリ High School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
火のないところに煙を立てて
Making smoke where there is no fire,
電車を飛び降り改札抜けたら 学校まではもうダッシュ
Jump off the train and through the turnstiles, full dash to school!
ツッパリ High School Rock'n Roll
Tsuppari High School Rock'n Roll!
またまた遅刻で今日も呼び出し
Late again today and called to the office.
オーケー、じゃあ！
Okay then!
サンキュー！
Thank you!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
またね！
See you!
バレる！
[Song: Bareru!]
Oh yeah ちょっと待って何これ知らぬ間に曲がり角 eh
Oh yeah, wait a second, what's this? Around the corner before I knew it, eh
Oh yeah どこにも見当たらない人の足跡 eh
Oh yeah, nowhere to be seen, not a trace of anyone's footprints, eh
胸の高さに押さえ送り込む肺に酸素また深くえっ
Holding at chest height, pushing oxygen deep into the lungs again, deep, eh
灰色のサンゴ礁 荒天の夕暮れ
A gray coral reef under a stormy twilight
Who's next?
次は誰が描き出す画期的な図
Who's drawing the next revolutionary diagram?
数千の屍掻き分け誰もが血眼
Pushing through thousands of corpses, everyone is frantic
上も下もパンパンな満員電車からスィー
Sliding smooth out of the packed train, jammed top and bottom
潜徳 顕われ見せつける特殊生えた力
Hidden virtue revealed, showing off newly spawned special powers
高く付いたあの追従
That costly follow-up
邪魔な雑音 解像度
Annoying noise, resolution
覚醒の内側へ
Into the inside of awakening
惑星の連鎖の呼び声
Calling out the chain of planets
Oh yeah えげつない物発明したのかも
Oh yeah, maybe something nasty's been invented
生中継
Live broadcast
革命前夜歓喜に湧く人々のラボ
On the eve of revolution, people in the lab overflow with joy
バレる
Exposed
この俺の天賦の才能がバレる
My natural talent is gonna get exposed
バレる
Exposed
マジこれでめんどくさいな
Seriously, this is gonna be such a pain
バレる
Exposed
世の中が気づかれる
The world is gonna find out
That's game! Voice like a weapon my heyday
とりあえずはヴィランだろ
For now, I'm the villain, right?
ほら見たことか苦み映る
See that? Bitterness reflected
Oh yeah 拍手と歓声 ここ日当たる場所
Oh yeah, applause and cheers, this sunlit spot
沈着冷静 地に足つけたままありがとう
Calm and collected, keeping my feet on the ground, thank you
知名度名声は水物 勝敗は空の箱
Fame and prestige are fickle, victory or defeat an empty box
って頭で分かっちゃいるくせに
Even though I know that in my head
体が増していく密着
My body gets increasingly tense
あの恐怖に向かってダッシュ
Dash towards that fear
液晶を丸め込むヒストリー
Rolling up the liquid crystal display history
ゲームなら一度のミスが命取り
In a game, a single mistake is fatal
見えて手のひら返しが一斉に
Visible palm flip all at once
白黒つけられない
Can't tell black from white
モンスターじゃ居られない
Can't stay a monster
やば失うものが
Oh crap, the things to lose...
欲しい 欲しい 欲しい 欲しい
I want, I want, I want, I want
俺をわかってくれと叫ぶように
As if shouting "Understand me!"
知らしめたばかりに
Just because I made it known
自分自身をより自分らしく演じなきゃいけない羽目に
Stuck having to act even more like myself
蜜の味 出たあの味
Sweet taste, that flavor came out
でも俺はもうそこには居ない
But I'm not there anymore
俺って誰？ 俺って何？
Who am I? What am I?
ビビって手元足元見ないで
Scared, don't look at your hands or feet
バレる
Exposed
俺にはもう何にもないや
I've got nothing left at all
バレる
Exposed
端から勘違いだった
It was a misunderstanding from the start
バレる
Exposed
化けの皮 剥がされる
My true colors are getting stripped away
That's game! Voice like a weapon my heyday
手を叩いて 指さして
Clap your hands, point your finger
ほら見たことか笑える
See that? It's laughable
生きている限りは勝ち逃げ出来ねえな
As long as you're alive, you can't quit while you're ahead
衰え錆びつき同化されてしまう定めか
Is it destiny to decay, rust, and be assimilated?
唾を吐いたのは
The one who spat
唾液を書いたのは
The one who wrote saliva
あの日の俺とよく似た目をしてたやつでした
Was a guy with eyes just like mine back then
あいにく俺はまだ
Unfortunately, I'm still...
渡れぬ賽の河原
The River Styx I cannot cross
今日もまた積み上げては蹴飛ばされる賽の河原
Stacking stones daily, only to be kicked over again at the River Styx
痛みが大飽きた
Sick and tired of the pain
ニヤリとノーエンダー
Grinning, no-ender
恩返しのパスあるかとな
Wondering if there's a pass to return the favor
バレる
Exposed
この俺の天賦の才能がバレる
My natural talent is gonna get exposed
バレる
Exposed
マジこれでめんどくさいな
Seriously, this is gonna be such a pain
バレる
Exposed
世の中が気づかれる
The world is gonna find out
That's game! Voice like a weapon my heyday
手を叩いて 指さして
Clap your hands, point your finger
ほら見たことか笑える
See that? It's laughable
ぺったんこ！
Flat as a pancake!
疲れる〜 つかれる〜 たにま〜
Exhausting~ So tired~ Cleavage~
こんちくわ
Konchikuwa
轟はじめ
Todoroki Hajime
こん！ ちくわ！ こん！ こん！ ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa!
ぶんぶんぶん
Bun bun bun
こん！ ちくわ！ こん！ こん！ ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa!
ちゅっ
Chu
おっ おっ おっ ふーん
Oh, oh, oh, hmm
泣いちゃうぞ
I'm gonna cry
ぴえん ぴえん おっ おっ おっ すごーい
Pien, pien, oh, oh, oh, awesome
チュッ すきっ おっ おっ おっ
Chu, love you, oh, oh, oh
チュッ 泣いちゃうぞ ぴえん ぴえん
Chu, I'm gonna cry, pien, pien
泣いちゃうぞ 泣いちゃうぞ ごみゃん
I'm gonna cry, I'm gonna cry, sowwy
こん！ ちくわ！ こん！ こん！ ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa!
最終手段 抱いてやる
Last resort: I'll hug you
こん！ ちくわ！ こんちくわ！ ちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Konchikuwa! Chikuwa!
ぴゃ！ ぴゃ！ ぴゃ？ ぴゃ！ あい！ あい！ げんき！
Pya! Pya! Pya? Pya! Ai! Ai! Genki!
カツオでき 仮想敵？ カツオでき 仮想敵？
Katsuo deki, virtual enemy? Katsuo deki, virtual enemy?
ぴゃ！ ぴゃ！ ぴゃ？ ぴゃ！ あい！ あい！ げんき！
Pya! Pya! Pya? Pya! Ai! Ai! Genki!
泣かれたら泣き返す 今を生きろよ やさしいじゃん
If cried at, I'll cry back; live in the moment; so sweet
こん！ ちくわ！ こん！ こんちくわ！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Konchikuwa!
こん！ ちくわ！ こん！ こん！ ちくわ！ 終わりー！
Kon! Chikuwa! Kon! Kon! Chikuwa! It's over~!
あのー ノエル先輩がね
Um, so Noel-senpai, you know,
ラップしてたんだよなー
was doing a rap...
ちょっと対抗してみようかな
I thought maybe I'd compete with her...
もうちょっと韻踏めない気がするけど
I feel like I can't really rhyme that well,
もう頭まわんなくて
and my brain isn't really working anymore...
よし！ これで行こう！
Alright! Let me go with this!
二日目！
Day two!
ノエルだんちょーに対抗！
Competing against Captain Noel!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the Rap Leader!
ラップでバトルしょーよー！
Let's do a rap battle!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the Rap Leader!
初テイムは ぶんぶんてんちょー
My first tame was Bunbun Manager!
初レイドで あっけなく終了ー
Ended abruptly on our first raid!
その次テイムしたの...
The next one I tamed...
アルゲンなんだよー
was an Argentavis!
トワさんとフブキさんで 大冒険だYO！
A great adventure with Towa-san and Fubuki-san, YO!
ビーバーとっこー！ セメント大量！
Beaver rush! Massive amounts of cement!
大成功でおわったYO！
Ended in huge success, YO!
もっと強くなるばんちょー
I'll get even stronger, Leader!
あ！おい！
Ah! Hey!
ノエルおまえ負けてんぞ！
Noel, you're losing!
時間無さすぎてラップできなかった未熟ものだよー
Having no time and failing to rap makes you an amateur!
おいおいヤバいやめろよ
Hey, hey, woah, stop it!
日記でラップバトル始めないでよ
Don't start a rap battle with your diary entries!
全然いいけど ラップバトル者かね
Though it's totally fine, as rap battlers...
二日目！
Day two!
ノエルだんちょーに対抗！
Competing against Captain Noel!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the Rap Leader!
ラップでバトルしょーよー！
Let's do a rap battle!
うちがらっぷばんちょー！
I'm the Rap Leader!
初テイムは ぶんぶんてんちょー
My first tame was Bunbun Manager!
初レイドで あっけなく終了ー
Ended abruptly on our first raid!
その次テイムしたの...
The next one I tamed...
アルゲンなんだよー
was an Argentavis!
トワさんとフブキさんで 大冒険だYO！
A great adventure with Towa-san and Fubuki-san, YO!
ビーバーとっこー！ セメント大量！
Beaver rush! Massive amounts of cement!
大成功でおわったYO！
Ended in huge success, YO!
もっと強くなるばんちょー
I'll get even stronger, Leader!
はい。番長の勝利。おめでとう。
Yes. Leader's victory. Congratulations.
I'm Koseki Bijou / アイム 一条はじめ
I'm Koseki Bijou / I'm Hajime Ichijou
Boom Boom Boom! / ぶんぶんぶん
Boom Boom Boom! / Bun bun bun
Nice to meet you / はじめまして
Nice to meet you / Nice to meet you
うたうー！ Let's go!
Sing! Let's go!
Cool? Yeah! Thank you, thank you
I'm Bancho Yeah!
I'm Leader, Yeah!
We were cool, right?
ベリベリハッピー Very very happy Thank you!
Very very happy! Very very happy! Thank you!
Can you say something for me?
Sticking out your gyatt for Nerizzler
なになになに！？ You're so Bau bau
What, what, what!? You're so Bau bau
You're so Biboo tax
I just wanna be your Shiori
Yeay! She said the thing!
Yay! She said the thing!
Sticking out your gyatt for Nerizzler...
This one!
Wow wow wow wow! Yeah!
Are you ready? Okey!
Are you ready? Okay!
Cool? Yeah! Thank you, thank you
I'm Bancho Yeah!
I'm Leader, Yeah!
We were cool, right?
ベリベリハッピー Very very happy Thank you!
Very very happy! Very very happy! Thank you!
I want to hear the word Bijou-senpai's "Ryourya"
I want to hear Bijou-senpai say "Ryourya"
はい？？
Huh??
頭いーてーよもう
My head hurts so much!
ぼろぼろ
I'm in tatters...
いまフワモコがばんちょー先生の所に向かってます！オーバー！
FuwaMoco is currently heading to Leader-sensei's location! Over!
ばんちょー先生だみゃ はじめ
It's Leader-sensei and Hajime!
ばんちょー先生いま持ってます 持たれてます
We're holding Leader-sensei! We're being held!
次はちょっとつめたいけどがまんしてねー！わ！つめたい！
It's a bit cold next, but hang in there! Woah, so cold!
OKじゃあ、次はハートマッサージね！ハートマッサージ？
OK then, next is a heart massage! Heart massage?
BAU BAU! BAU BAU! BAU BAU!
大丈夫！
It'll be okay!
あいびりーぶゆぅ
I believe you!
BAU BAU! ソーセージ！
BAU BAU! Sausage!
おなかが痛いよー ぜんぶ大丈夫になるからね
My tummy hurts! Everything will be alright!
これで大丈夫かなー！ げんきになったぁ！
Is this good now!? I'm feeling better!
BAU BAU! これからも病院がんばろうねー！
BAU BAU! Let's keep doing our best at the hospital!
殴り合いますか？ あ、殴り合う？いいよ ちょっといま溜まってるわ
Shall we fight? Ah, brawl? Sure, I've got built-up stress right now.
やめてw まあ久々にやるからね ちょっできるか
Stop it, lol! Well, it's been a while, let me see if I still got it.
イクゾッ！ ドド能力！ イヤー！ 勝つ！ 負けねぇ！
Let's go! Dododo! Yaah! I'll win! I won't lose!
勝つ！ やめろー！
I'll win! Stop it!
イヤ〜！
Nooo!
俺の勝ち！ 完全勝利！
I win! Total victory!
ボール持って モチュッ ピュイ〜 ポイツ
Hold the ball, squish! Pyui~ toss!
チョイチョイ チョイチョイ チョイチョイ ピュイ〜
Choi choi, choi choi, choi choi, pyui~
えいっ えいっ えいっ あいやー えいっ えいっ
Ei! Ei! Ei! Aiya~ Ei! Ei!
Yes, I do.
ぶんぶんぶーん ぱんちょー ぶんぶんぶんぶんぶーん あみゃみゃみゃみゃみゃー
Bun bun bun, banjo~ bun bun bun bun bun, amyamyamyamyamya~
轟はじめです またの名を ただの甘えん坊だ
I'm Todoroki Hajime, also known as a total spoiled brat.
白銀ノエル またの名を 牛丼太郎だ
I'm Shirogane Noel, also known as Gyudon Taro.
よろしくな よろしくな
Nice to meet ya, nice to meet ya!
イヤ〜！
Nooo!
イヤアアアアー！
Nooooo!
俺の勝ち 完全勝利
I win! Total victory!
なんなんだ このゲーム！
What is this game?!
気合いじゃどうにもならんかったか
Guess fighting spirit wasn't enough...
どうも もるでちおです
Hello, I'm Moru Dechio.
でび様に負けたので
Since I lost to Debiru-sama...
今からでび様考案の うんちぷりぷりだんすをします
I'm now going to do the Poop Puripuri Dance created by Debiru-sama.
うん・ちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うん・ちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Un-cha purya-purya, un-cha purya-purya,
うん・ちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うん・ちゃ
Un-cha purya-purya, un-cha!
うん・ちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うん・ちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Un-cha purya-purya, un-cha purya-purya,
異界の扉 開かれ中 から来た
Coming from inside the opening door of another world,
轟はじめ またの名を はじ・はじ・はじめ よろしく
I'm Todoroki Hajime, also known as Haji-Haji-Hajime. Nice to meet ya!
悪魔中から来た でびでび・でびる またの名を うんちうんちうんち
Coming from inside the demon realm, Debidebi Debiru, also known as Poop-Poop-Poop!
うんち うんち うんち... うんち王
Poop, poop, poop... Poop King!
はじめまして ありがとうございま... 来てくだちって
Nice to meet you! Thank you for... coming over!
じゃあ今度僕が踊って言ったら踊ってくれる？
Then next time I say 'dance', will you dance for me?
うん・ちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ うん・ちゃ ぷりゃぷりゃ
Un-cha purya-purya, un-cha purya-purya,
またね またあそんでください
See ya! Please play with me again!
また遊んでやるよ
I'll play with you again!
やったー！
Yay!
せーのっ おつもるでちお〜
Ready, set... Otsu-Moru-Dechio~!
うわー！ すごい楽しいコラボだったー！
Whoa~! That was such a fun collab!
あれ？ ちょ、カメラちゃん、こっちこっちー
Huh? Wait, Mr. Camera, over here, over here!
こっちこっちー、うわ
Over here! Whoa!
いやー、すごい楽しかったー！
Man, that was so much fun!
あとトレンドも1位に入ったっちゅうことなんですかね？ ありがとうございます！
And I hear we hit #1 on trending? Thank you so much!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
えー、ReGLOSSのみんなと、ベイちゃんと、ぺこら先輩、マリン先輩、フレン先輩、ノエル先輩、でびちゃん
Um, everyone from ReGLOSS, Bae-chan, Pekora-senpai, Marine-senpai, Furen-senpai, Noel-senpai, and Debidebi-chan...
という豪華10名のゲストが来てくださいましたー！ うれちーや！
A gorgeous lineup of 10 guests came to join! I'm so happy!
あの最後のやつは、はじめのやる気出ない動画を作ってくれたおたまよ先生のこれまでの作品をメドレーにしてもらいまちた！
That last one was a medley of Otamayo-sensei's past works, who made Hajime's unmotivated video!
可愛いメドレーありがとうございます！
Thank you for the cute medley!
ま、このメドレー以外にもね、いろんな作品作ってるので、ぜひいろいろ見てください
Besides this medley, they've made many other works, so please check them out!
もう本当に先輩も同期もみんな来てくれて、にじさんじさんからでびちゃんも来てくれて、ほんと嬉ちー！ またコラボしてほしいなー！
I'm so glad my senpais, genmates, and even Debidebi-chan from Nijisanji came! I hope we collab again!
はい、ということで、えー
Alright, so...
みなさん、どうですか？
How is it, everyone?
3D chibi 姿の、いつも通り可愛いだろ？ 可愛いだろ？
My 3D chibi form is cute as always, right? Cute, right?
ま、でもね、ちょっとこれからまたダンスを披露したいので
Well, but I want to show off another dance now...
えっと、ちょっとね、ダンス見えやすいようにストレッチしてくるわ。ちょっと待ってて？ ちょっと待ってて？
So I'm gonna go stretch so the dance is easier to see. Wait a sec, okay? Wait a sec!
ボキボキ... うわー、疲れたー
*crack crack* Wow, I'm tired...
固くなってたわー。伸びた伸びた
I was so stiff. Stretched out now!
ということでね、次の曲行きたいと思います！
And with that, let's move on to the next song!
聴いてください。『ワールドイズマイン』
Please listen: 'World is Mine'.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気がつくこと
Number 1: Notice when my hairstyle is different than usual.
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね？
Number 2: Make sure to check down to my shoes, got it?
その三 私の一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Number 3: Reply with three words to every single thing I say.
分かったら右手がお留守なのなんとかして！
If you get it, do something about my empty right hand!
別にわがままなんて言っていないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
キミに心から思ってほしいの かわいいって
I just want you to truly think I'm cute from the bottom of your heart.
世界で一番おひめさま
I'm the number one princess in the world,
気がついて ねぇねぇ
So notice me, hey, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question.
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もうなんだか
Man, somehow...
甘いものが食べたい！
I really want to eat something sweet!
今すぐによ
Right this instant!
Check 1, 2
欠点？ かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You must mean cute.
文句は許しませんの
Complaints will not be tolerated.
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いてる？ ちょっとー！
Hey, are you even listening to me? Excuse me!
あ、それとね 白いお馬さん 決まってるでしょ？
Oh, and also, a white horse is obvious, right?
迎えに来て
Come pick me up.
分かったらひざまずいて
If you understand, kneel down,
手を取っておひめさまって
Take my hand, and call me "My Princess."
別にわがままなんて言っていないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
でもね
But you know...
少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
It's okay if you scold me just a little bit, you know?
世界でわたしだけの王子様
The prince that belongs only to me in the whole world,
気がついて ほらほら
Notice me, look, look!
お手手が開いています
My hand is completely open!
無愛想で無口な王子様
My blunt and quiet prince...
もう！ どうして？
Jeez! Why?
気がついてよ 早く！
Notice me already, hurry!
ぜったい君は分かってない！
You definitely don't get it!
分かってないわ...
You just don't get it...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Strawberry shortcake,
こだわりたまごの とろけるプリン
Melting pudding made with special eggs...
みんな みんな 我慢します
I'll endure all of them, all of them.
わがままな子だと思わないで
Don't think of me as a selfish girl.
わたしだってやればできるもん
I can do it if I try!
後で後悔するわよ
You'll regret it later, you know.
当然です！だってわたしは
Naturally! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world.
ちゃんと見ててよね
Keep your eyes on me, okay?
どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Or I might wander off somewhere, you know?
ふいに抱きしめられた
Suddenly, I was embraced.
急に そんな え？
So suddenly... wait, huh?
「轢かれる 危険だよ」
"You'll get hit, it's dangerous."
そう言ってそっぽ向く キミ
Saying that, you turned away...
...こっちのが危険だわよ
...This is way more dangerous!
街の明かりがにじんでる
The city lights are blurring,
そっと手々触れそうな
A crescent moon that feels close enough to touch gently,
三日月
A crescent moon.
あなたに会える特別な日は
On this special day when I can meet you,
指先キラメくダイヤモンドで
with sparkling diamonds on my fingertips,
いつもよりゆっくり
walking slower than usual,
いつもよりも早く
arriving earlier than usual,
一緒にいたくて
just because I want to be with you...
慣れないハイヒール よろめいちゃうから
These unfamiliar high heels make me stumble,
腕を貸して そんなの...
so lend me your arm—is that...
見栄えかしら？
just for show?
恋はイリュージョン 少しロマンチック
Love is an illusion, a little romantic.
予想できないストーリー 聞かせて
Tell me an unpredictable story.
恋はイリュージョン 少しファンタスティック
Love is an illusion, a little fantastic.
隠しきれないこの胸のドキドキ
I can't hide this fluttering in my heart.
瞳閉じてみたら
If I close my eyes,
シュワシュワシュワシュワ
fizz, fizz, fizz, fizz...
聞こえてくるでしょう
You can hear it, right?
映画のワンシーンみたいに
Just like a scene in a movie,
きゅんとする仕草 リサーチしても
even if I research gestures that make hearts throb,
あなたに会った瞬間
the moment I meet you,
全部あいまい
it all gets blurred.
揺れている
Swaying,
ピンクサファイア
a pink sapphire...
言葉より目と目
Eyes speak louder than words...
目と目より心で通じ合っても
Even if our hearts connect beyond our eyes...
慣れない静けさに 緊張しちゃうから
This unfamiliar silence makes me nervous,
微笑んでね そんなの...
so give me a smile—is that...
贅沢かしら？
too much to ask?
恋はイリュージョン 甘いテンプテーション
Love is an illusion, a sweet temptation.
予想できないストーリー 聞かせて
Tell me an unpredictable story.
恋はイリュージョン 甘いテンプテーション
Love is an illusion, a sweet temptation.
隠しきれないこの胸のドキドキ
I can't hide this fluttering in my heart.
シャンパンの泡のような
Like the bubbles in champagne,
シュワシュワシュワシュワ
fizz, fizz, fizz, fizz...
はじけているでしょう
It's popping, isn't it?
恋はイリュージョン すごいロマンチック
Love is an illusion, so romantic.
予想してない愛おしさで包まれ
Wrapped in an unexpected tenderness,
恋はイリュージョン かなりファンタスティック
Love is an illusion, quite fantastic.
隠しきれないこの胸のドキドキ
I can't hide this fluttering in my heart.
瞳閉じてみたら
If I close my eyes,
シュワシュワシュワシュワ
fizz, fizz, fizz, fizz...
聞こえてくるでしょう
You can hear it, right?
いつまで子供のままでいる？
"How long will you stay a child?"
そんな言葉がふりかかる
Such words rain down on me.
黙って見てればいいんだ
"Just shut up and watch."
笑ってそう言ってやれ
Smile and tell them that!
人生にはないんだ take 2
There are no take 2s in life.
平凡でくだらない退屈
Ordinary, foolish boredom...
なんてごめんだ 現実的な
No thanks to that! Realistic...
言葉なんかには耳をふさげ
words, block your ears to them all!
ネバーランドに閉じこもって
Shutting yourself in Neverland,
いつまでだって夢を語るんだ
keep talking about dreams forever.
笑う奴には唾を吐け
Spit on those who laugh at you.
にっちもさっちもいかない？
Are you stuck between a rock and a hard place?
綺麗事に踊り踊らされ
Dancing to clean-cut platitudes,
大人の言う常識なんてものは
whatever "common sense" adults talk about...
丸めて捨てちまへ
Roll it up and throw it away!
ピーターパン症候群と
Called Peter Pan Syndrome,
指をさされ 罵られようが
pointed at, and cursed at as I may be...
おとぎ話みたいなハッピーエンドを
A fairytale-like happy ending,
思い描いて生きていくんだ
I'll live picturing it in my mind!
こっち指差して笑ってんだろう
You're pointing over here and laughing at me, aren't you?
好きに笑えよ それで別にいいさ
Laugh all you want, it doesn't bother me at all.
お前なんかになにも言われたくない
I don't want to hear a thing from the likes of you.
黙って見てろ
Just shut up and watch.
やり直しのきかない人生
In a life where there are no do-overs,
一度でいい チャンスをください
Just give me one chance.
掴んで放さない
I'll grab it and never let go,
もう俺のものなんだ
It's already mine!
ネバーランドの大気圏を
Breaking through Neverland's atmosphere,
破って今夢を叶えるんだ
I'm going to make my dream come true right now.
笑う奴など蹴り飛ばせ
Kick aside anyone who dares to laugh!
打つ手はない 残されてない？ は？
"No options left? Nothing remaining?" Huh?
ネガティブを押し付けてくんな
Don't push your negativity on me.
大人のあんたも知らない世界を
In a world that even you adults don't know,
俺は生きてるんだ
I'm living my life.
ピーターパン症候群と思われたって 馬鹿にされたって
Even if they call it Peter Pan Syndrome, even if they make fun of me,
おとぎ話みたいなハッピーエンドに
Towards a fairytale-like happy ending,
一直線に進んで行くんだ
I'll head straight forward!
夢の見過ぎと馬鹿にされた少年が
A boy mocked for dreaming too much,
夢を掴む物語を
A story of seizing dreams...
見事な逆転劇をこの手で
A splendid reversal drama with my own hands,
巻き起こせ 見せつけてやれ
I'll trigger it! Show it off to them!
にっちもさっちもいかないよ
"Stuck in a complete deadlock,"
綺麗事に踊り踊らされ
Danced around by sugarcoated ideals,
大人の言う常識なんてものは
Common sense preached by adults,
丸めて捨てちまえ
Just roll it up and throw it away!
ピーターパン症候群と指をさされ 嗤われようが
Even if they point fingers at Peter Pan Syndrome and laugh,
おとぎ話みたいなハッピーエンドを
A fairytale-like happy ending,
そう自ら掴み取るんだ
Yes, I'll grasp it with my own hands!
Woah oh oh...
はい！
Yes!
えー、可愛い、可愛い！ 言われて一番言った！
Um, "cute, cute!" You said it so much!
えー、初めてタップに挑戦しました！
Um, I tried tap dancing for the first time!
声は？ 絶好調！
How's my voice? In top shape!
そして、初めての歌枠で歌った、初めての大好きな曲の、DECO*27さんの「ピーターパン」でした！
And that was DECO*27's "Peter Pan," the very first song I sang on my first singing stream, a song I love!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
えー、次はオリ曲を2曲やっていきまーす！
Um, next, I'm going to perform two original songs!
え？ オリ曲2曲？ え、そんな持ってたっけ？ ちょ、ちょっと待ってね。
Huh? Two original songs? Wait, did I have that many? Wait, hold on a sec.
「Countach」そして、新曲が出まーす！
"Countach", and a new song is coming out!
2曲続けて聴いてください！
Please listen to these two songs back-to-back!
それでは、聴いてください、「Countach」！
Now then, please listen to "Countach"!
誰かのため頑張んの 報われない Day by day
Working hard for someone else, unrewarded day by day,
結局 正直者が 道化師で踊る残像
In the end, honest people dance like fools as fading traces.
誰？
Who?
要領よく生きてるあの子 懐に舞い込む
That person living shrewdly gets blessings handed to them,
言うた事無いでしょう？
They've never experienced it, have they?
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra,
開けるよ パンドラ
I'm opening Pandora's box,
抑えきれないのさ
I just can't hold it back!
歌う歌 サンドラ
Singing a song, sound like Sandra,
シェイクスピアも鳴らすアラーム
An alarm that even Shakespeare would set off,
暴れまくるぜ カニバル
Going wild like a carnival!
Everybody gonna put your hands 喰らえ 喰らえ まだ見ぬ世界へ飛び込め 3 2 1
Everybody gonna put your hands, take this, take this! Jump into an unseen world, 3 2 1!
あがれ感情へ
Soar into emotion,
体揺らして
Shake your body!
ほら既成概念 あるがままぶち壊せ
Look, break down preconceived notions just as they are!
あがれ感情へ
Soar into emotion,
体揺らして
Shake your body!
ほら既成概念 あるがままぶち壊せ
Look, break down preconceived notions just as they are!
Countach 最上級の Countach
Countach, top-tier Countach,
Countach 一新プランで Countach
Countach, with a brand-new plan, Countach!
Countach イントロの Countach
Countach, from the intro Countach,
Countach 何度だって Countach
Countach, no matter how many times, Countach!
息をひそめて自分を 殺すのはもう慣れてんの
Holding my breath and killing my true self, I'm used to it by now.
存在価値 存在証明なんて どうでもいいわ
Worth of existence, proof of existence... I don't care about any of that!
宴ならエンドレス 宵宵と払うはずかま Borderless
If it's a banquet, it's endless, brushing away the night, borderless...
メッセージの雷 帯びて Powerful 弾け飛んで理性を
Charged with lightning messages, powerful, blasting away all reason!
アブラカタブラ
Abracadabra,
開けるよ パンドラ
I'm opening Pandora's box,
抑えきれないのさ
I just can't hold it back!
ダークサングラス
Dark sunglasses,
本性カムフラージュ 本能だけで十分混ざり合う
Camouflaging true nature, mixing together with pure instinct.
Everybody gonna put your hands clap clap
明日のことは忘れろ 3 2 1
Forget about tomorrow, 3, 2, 1!
(Doubt) 叫べてっぺんへ
(Doubt) Shout out to the top!
(Doubt) 声をからして
(Doubt) Sing until your voice goes hoarse!
(Doubt) 君だけの人生 楽しまなきゃ損じゃない？
(Doubt) It's your own life, if you don't enjoy it, isn't it a waste?
(Doubt) 叫べてっぺんへ
(Doubt) Shout out to the top!
(Doubt) 声をからして
(Doubt) Sing until your voice goes hoarse!
(Doubt) 君だけの人生 楽しまなきゃ損じゃない？
(Doubt) It's your own life, if you don't enjoy it, isn't it a waste?
6pm 鳴るアラーム
6 PM alarm ringing,
あぶれ者 crew, like a carnival
Outcast crew, like a carnival!
Everybody gonna put your hands clap clap
まだ見ぬ世界飛び込め 3 2 1
Dive into a world yet unseen, 3, 2, 1!
Are you ready?
(Doubt) I got it 段上へ
(Doubt) I got it, onto the stage!
(Doubt) 体揺らして
(Doubt) Sway your body!
(Doubt) ほら既成概念 あるがままぶち壊せ
(Doubt) Hey, smash those fixed concepts as they are!
(Doubt) I got it 段上へ
(Doubt) I got it, onto the stage!
(Doubt) 体揺らして
(Doubt) Sway your body!
(Doubt) ほら既成概念 あるがままぶち壊せ
(Doubt) Hey, smash those fixed concepts as they are!
Countach 最上級の Countach
Countach, top-tier Countach!
(Da-da) Countach 一心不乱で Countach
(Da-da) Countach, whole-heartedly Countach!
(Da-da) Countach in to you no Countach
Countach 何度だって Countach
Countach, time and time again, Countach!
バンザイ無能な命に
Hurrah for a useless life!
くだらないよ 紛い物だってば ラリアッチュー
It's foolish, even if it's a fake, lariattchu!
偶然息してるようなもん
It's like I'm just breathing by chance.
不条理浴びながら僕は Home
Showered in absurdity, I'm home.
才能はゼロ
Zero talent,
どうにかしちまっちゃってるキャラ
a character who somehow messed up completely.
歓声は No だって
Cheers are a "No," and yet...
愛にもたれた言葉で心拍数
Heart rate rising with words leaning on love,
生きてく程胸は沈んでゆく
the more I live, the deeper my heart sinks.
どうなってんだろうな？ この音が揺れるの
What is going on? This sound sways...
かいつまんでもしょうがねぇ
Summarizing it won't help.
汗かき稼ぐお金はどんだけ？
How much money do I earn sweating it out?
あぁだこうだ
Saying this and that,
そんなもんか
is that all it is?
五月蝿ぇわな
So noisy, isn't it?
バンザイ無能な命に
Hurrah for a useless life!
空回っていく脳を満たしてくれ
Fill my mind that's spinning uselessly.
未来予想図なんか描けない
I can't draw any vision for the future.
くだらないよ 紛い物だってそれ
It's foolish, that's just a fake too.
半端者ならやれない nutty tune
A nutty tune that half-hearted ones can't pull off.
朱色になって僕は思い通り
Turning crimson, everything goes my way.
太陽系で踊った
Danced in the solar system,
罵詈雑言インベーダー
abusive language invader.
足が止まっているシューゲイザー
A shoegazer with stopped feet,
死にそうでもギリですか
even if about to die, is it barely hanging on?
のらりくらりかわすわ
Dodging lazily and smoothly.
初めまして神様
Nice to meet you, God.
もし救われるのなら腹切るわ今から
If I can be saved, I'll disembowel myself right now.
Get down 揺らめく
Get down, swaying.
Get down 飲み込んだ
Get down, swallowed down.
清濁が君を狂わしてんだ
Good and evil are driving you crazy.
滅多なもんじゃおどろかねぇ
Ordinary things won't surprise me.
汗かき生きた最期もあっけねぇ
The end of a life lived sweating is anti-climactic.
なんだかんだ
One way or another,
そんなもんさ
that's just how it is.
虚しいわな
It feels empty, doesn't it?
バンザイ無能な命に
Hurrah for a useless life!
空回っていく脳を満たしてくれ
Fill my mind that's spinning uselessly.
未来予想図なんか描けない
I can't draw any vision for the future.
くだらないよ 紛い物だってそれ
It's foolish, that's just a fake too.
半端者ならやれない nutty tune
A nutty tune that half-hearted ones can't pull off.
朱色になって僕は思い通り
Turning crimson, everything goes my way.
はい！ということで、生誕グッズが出ます！
Alright! So with that, my birthday merch is out!
轟はじめ生誕祭記念2025！
Todoroki Hajime Birthday Celebration 2025!
フルセットはこちらな感じでーす！
The full set looks like this!
1つずつ紹介していきます！
Let me introduce them one by one!
1つ目！アクリルパネル！Aちき先生の可愛いイラストと...
First! Acrylic panel! Featuring cute art by A-chiki-sensei...
ホロ加工になってます！何やらジャケットを着用しているようでめちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It has a holographic finish! She's wearing the jacket, super cute!
2つ目！BANCHOアクリルキーホルダー！おもちチャウダー先生の...
Second! BANCHO acrylic keychains! By Omochi Chowder-sensei...
番長イラストです！3つ繋げても、1つずつでも使えます！
Bancho illustrations! You can connect all three or use them separately!
カラビナはイカの形になってます！
The carabiner is shaped like a squid!
ぜひカバンとかに繋げてみようね！
Be sure to attach them to your bags!
3つ目！BANCHOナイロンジャケット！
Third! BANCHO nylon jacket!
こちらは、実際に実物で色味をチェックして使いやすいデザインにしました！
I checked the colors on the physical sample to make it easy to wear!
おもちチャウダー先生のミニ番長イラストと、表にははじめの考えた番長ロゴが付いてます！
It features Omochi Chowder-sensei's mini Bancho art, and the front has the logo Hajime designed!
チャックもイカの形になってます！キービジュアルのはじめとお揃いのデザインです！
The zipper is squid-shaped too! It matches Hajime's key visual outfit!
最後！シチュエーションボイス！ナイロンジャケットにまつわるボイスです！よかったら合わせて聴いてください！
Lastly! Situation Voice! A voice clip about the nylon jacket! Please listen to it too!
今回、フルセット購入特典は2つあります！
This time, there are two full set purchase bonuses!
1つ目！直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイド！
First! Cheki-style bromide with a handwritten signature!
複製メッセージ付きになってます！このライブが良かったなと思ってくださったら、次回以降のライブの励みになるので、ぜひよろしくお願いします！
It includes a printed message! If you enjoyed this live, it'll encourage future lives, so please check it out!
2つ目！オフィシャルショップにて購入された方限定で、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使えるカードが1枚つきます！
Second! Official Shop exclusive—get 1 card playable in the Hololive Official Card Game!
カードの詳細や遊び方については、公式ホームページを見てください！
Check the official website for card details and rules!
以上、グッズ紹介でした！
That's all for the merch intro!
行きしょう！まだまだ踊っていくので、ぜひ最後まで見てください！
Let's go! I'm gonna keep dancing, so please watch till the end!
それじゃあ、行け！はじめたんしゃーきゅー！
Alright then, go! Hajime Tan Thank You!
イエーイ！
Yay!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
みんな、こっちくまー！
Everyone over here-kuma!
はい、こっちの皆さんもー！こっちくまー！
Everyone over here too! Come here-kuma!
クラップ！
Clap!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
みんな、本当にライブ来てくれてありがとうねー！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to the live!
はい！ということで、みんな本当ありがとうございます！
Alright! So with that, thank you all so much!
このあと21時、新曲『BANCHO』のMVプレミア公開！そしてグッズ販売も開始されます！
At 21:00, the MV premier of my new song "BANCHO"! Plus merch sales start too!
そして、そのあとはメンバー限定のアンコールライブもあります！
And after that, there's a members-only encore live!
時間ぴったり！うわー、嬉しい！
Right on time! Wow, I'm so happy!
あの、トレンドもね！ありがとうございます！本当にみんなありがとうー！
Also, for trending on Twitter! Thank you so much! Truly, thank you everyone!
本当にありがとうー！
Thank you so much!
みなさん！！ いつも応援ありがとう！！
Everyone!! Thank you so much for your continuous support!!
ずっと夢だった生誕LIVEができて本当に幸せです！！
I'm so happy to finally hold the birthday live I've always dreamed of!!
次のステージでもっとパワーアップして、
I'll power up even more for the next stage,
毎回最高峰を更新させるぞ〜！
and keep reaching new heights every time!